[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e076fcbed638185eaa19", "question": "What was the first country to legalize same-sex marriage?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa56f73838c5c8a417f25", "question": "Which insect has the shortest lifespan?", "answer": "Mayfly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90e", "question": "What major river runs through Dublin?", "answer": "Liffey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd7", "question": "What kind of cheese is most commonly sold in the US as processed \"string cheese\"?", "answer": "Mozzarella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eea308d98002fdd633d6", "question": "\"Confide in Me\" was a hit in 1994 for which singer?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dde", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"mammoth\"?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a069", "question": "Anna Maria Louisa Italiano changed her name to what?", "answer": "Anne Bancroft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef32ea6ce05a3942286dff", "question": "How many U.S. states are needed to ratify an amendment for it to become part of the constitution?", "answer": "Three-fourths", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa81d73838c5c8a417f3a", "question": "How many noses does a slug have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68d", "question": "What modern-day US state was inhabited by the Calusa Indians?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cd0c877e98cb97778a31", "question": "Where is the Whistler Ski Resort located?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb47", "question": "Within 3 years, either way, in what year did Lou Gehrig deliver his famous farewell speech at Yankee Stadium?", "answer": "1939", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc7", "question": "The dish, Cullen Skink, originates from which country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d6", "question": "What is the name of the strait of water that separates the two main islands of New Zealand?", "answer": "Cook Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2a", "question": "What 1973 horror movie features the characters Father Merrin and Father Karras?", "answer": "The Exorcist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b41", "question": "What was the short lived game show that Betty White won an Emmy award for hosting in 1983?", "answer": "Just Men!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c259", "question": "What is another name for tetanus?", "answer": "Lockjaw", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae2", "question": "Which British prime minister was awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c9c3877e98cb977789fc", "question": "Pago Pago is the capital of which country", "answer": "American Samoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a16", "question": "What is Bridget Jones' home city?", "answer": "London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbeb76ce05a3942286ef5", "question": "What famous singer was nicknamed \"Chairman of the Board\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd9e96ce05a3942286d7e", "question": "What was the name of the girl in the film \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Lex Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904998ccf93664eb1048692", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ba", "question": "Which Seinfeld character takes his shirt off when he visits the toilet?", "answer": "George Costanza", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab69", "question": "Which major Australia city does the Fremantle city port serve?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e9", "question": "In which country would you find the world's oldest golf course?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4e", "question": "What was the name of the first Sony-branded transistor radio?", "answer": "The TR-55", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062b11c9d816e292245c1d", "question": "What American artist is known for word paintings?", "answer": "Ed Ruscha (His\u00a0artistic training was rooted in commercial art.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf7", "question": "What was the agora in an ancient Greek city?", "answer": "Marketplace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cc", "question": "What animal's head is placed on a stick in \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "A pig's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a5", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e9", "question": "Which herb is used to make \"Pesto Sauce\"", "answer": "Basil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb4", "question": "In telephony, what do the initials ISDN stand for?", "answer": "Integrated Services for Digital Network", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d8", "question": "In The Simpsons, what hangs on the wall directly to the right of the refridgerator in the Simpson's kitchen?", "answer": "Telephone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e92c77ccba3ffe45786bc", "question": "In which book does Flora refers to Mr. Meyerburg as Mr. Mybug?", "answer": "Cold Comfort Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b267", "question": "What empress gave John Paul Jones a navy job after his American military career ended?", "answer": "Catherine the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da5", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Being There\"?", "answer": "Jack Warden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b7", "question": "What name is given to twins who are joined together by some part of their anatomy?", "answer": "Siamese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6c", "question": "What round-bottomed cooking vessel did China introduce to the culinary world?", "answer": "The wok", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaec", "question": "What is the capital of Tanzania?", "answer": "Dodoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062be2c9d816e292245c26", "question": "Which Henri Matisse painting was hung upside down at the Museum of Modern Art in New York for 46 days without anyone noticing?", "answer": "Le Bateau (\"The Boat\"), a paper-cut, caused a stir in 1961 when the Museum of Modern Art in New York hung the work upside-down.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa4f86ce05a3942286eba", "question": "What duo first recorded the song \"Careless Whisper\"?", "answer": "Wham!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b3", "question": "Which movie was the first feature film made entirely in CGI?", "answer": "Toy Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d06ca9870e6f05ba600854", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Moneychangers\"?", "answer": "Arthur Hailey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7b36ff048f679a45abf4", "question": "What species of whale is known for singing long, complex songs?", "answer": "Humpback whales", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b244", "question": "What future secretary of state became US's first five-star general in 1944?", "answer": "George Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49e", "question": "Which European country is stereotypically associated with tulips, windmills and clogs?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be47", "question": "What does the abbreviation MPEG stand for in the video and audio compressing format?", "answer": "Moving Picture Experts Group", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339627", "question": "What was the name of the town the filmmakers visited in the movie \"The Blair With Project\"?", "answer": "Burkittesville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb671b5dad637d903c883b", "question": "If you order \"murgh\" from the menu at an Indian restaurant, what meat will you get?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323475bf195a31e15d73a6", "question": "What is the narrow, inland sea, separates the western Asia from northeastern Africa?", "answer": "Red sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a296", "question": "Billy Joel's \"Uptown Girl\" music video featured which supermodel?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25a6bb63e5727cf5a4853", "question": "Which rapper had hits including \"Who Am I (What's My Name)?\" and \"Gin And Juice\"?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a81", "question": "Edie Sedgwick was a protege of what artist?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bfe0233b668d7dfe168b5cb", "question": "In Greek mythology, Atlas was a member of what group?", "answer": "The Titans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca83", "question": "Which scientist is credited with inventing margarine?", "answer": "Hippolyte Mege-Mouries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ae", "question": "What year did J. D. Salinger publish the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f5", "question": "What band recorded the album \"A Night at the Opera\"?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d9", "question": "What was the official name of the first Indiana Jones movies?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c786", "question": "Edward J. Claghorn was granted the first patent for what safety device in 1885?", "answer": "Safety belts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a228", "question": "In what year was Puff Daddy's \"I'll Be Missing You\" song released?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e8", "question": "Which boat\u00a0passed through the Sea of\u00a0Green, the Sea of Holes and\u00a0the Sea of Time?", "answer": "The Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae862267f28483af1e7fdc6", "question": "Who was the author of the novel \"War and Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba68", "question": "In 1984, what computer company introduced the PC junior?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c917", "question": "Hans Lippershey made the worlds first practical what?", "answer": "Telescope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77b", "question": "What reptile's image is the logo of a popular French sportswear company?", "answer": "The crocodile's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949f", "question": "Who played the role of Mayor Randall Winston on the TV show \"Spin City\"?", "answer": "Barry Bostwick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973f", "question": "Which Disney film included the songs \"Chim Chim Cheree\" and \"Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious\"?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b788", "question": "What style of pants is named after an island in the Gulf of Naples?", "answer": "Capri pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d42", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"V for Vendetta\"?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46a", "question": "What is known as the Old Lady Of Threadneedle Street?", "answer": "The Bank of England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3cf7c73aa70ea0b70af1", "question": "Where will you find the Beagle Channel?", "answer": "In Tierra del Fuego Archipelago on the southern tip of South America between Chile and Argentina.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a1c612f2a7826b9b8715", "question": "What milk is Pecorino cheese made from?", "answer": "Ewe's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae37", "question": "What international award did President Theodore Roosevelt win in 1906?", "answer": "Nobel Peace Prize", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b40201dd7bf43be5e7b9", "question": "What library has the most books in the U.S.?", "answer": "The Library of Congress", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc5", "question": "How long is a fortnight?", "answer": "Two weeks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6b", "question": "Who was the number 1 ranked male tennis player the most years during the 1970\u2019s?", "answer": "Jimmy Connors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988e", "question": "In the 1964 stop-motion TV special \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\", who is Rudolph's father?", "answer": "Donner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e7", "question": "Which 1994 movie introduced the world to the characters Dante Hicks and Randal Graves?", "answer": "Clerks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cefc199948005ec986edce6", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600b88bb1d8c1817608d53f6", "question": "What is New York City's largest store?", "answer": "Macy's -- The flagship Macy\u2019s in Manhattan\u2019s Herald Square covers an entire NYC block, with 2.2 million sq. ft. of retail space.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab4fa0b8cce1e6fda7049", "question": "What English word has the most definitions/meanings?", "answer": "Run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a905", "question": "What major river runs through Vienna?", "answer": "Danube", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0da", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Republican Speaker of the House in 40 years?", "answer": "Newt Gingrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20c", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6a", "question": "Who was killed by John Wilkes Booth?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0de3ffcbed638185eaa14", "question": "In which U.S. state did the world's largest recorded snowflake fall?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c131877e98cb97778975", "question": "Where is Grant\u2019s Tomb?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d5", "question": "In 1991, who finally broke Bob Beamon's decades-old long jump record?", "answer": "Mike Powell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339055", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, italy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2137431a458464a93c44f", "question": "Which school was Maya Lin attending when she designed the Vietnam Veterans Memorial as part of a class assignment?", "answer": "Yale University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa3c86ce05a3942286ea9", "question": "Which famous writer was San Francisco's first Black female streetcar conductor?", "answer": "Maya Angelou", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede5de6ce05a3942286df2", "question": "What stop-motion animated film by Tim Burton stars Johnny Depp and Helena Bonham Carter?", "answer": "\"Corpse Bride\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17f", "question": "Who succeeded Pierre Trudeau as the 16th Prime Minister of Canada?", "answer": "Joe Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971e10289261e916c8e09b1", "question": "Which European city is the game \"Assassins Creed Unity\" set in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cdf", "question": "The poet Ogden Nash wrote \"Candy is dandy, but liquor is...\" what?", "answer": "Quicker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c987877e98cb977789f5", "question": "Which Pennsylvania town is the birthplace of \"Rolling Rock Beer\"?", "answer": "Latrobe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c1", "question": "In pool, what color is the 5-ball?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ef", "question": "When Forrest Gump was in the army, what sport was he good at?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaff", "question": "Thunder Bay is located in which country?", "answer": "Canada\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc8e1cf6db9ac4808d00", "question": "What is Montreal named after?", "answer": "A hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ae", "question": "How many ghosts appear to Scrooge in Dicken's \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59675d002b59efe0e9417e96", "question": "The color of your tongue is pink only if it's what?", "answer": "Germ-free", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5956434b803c1f1ebcc4a02f", "question": "The human heart weighs less than what?", "answer": "A pound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beef", "question": "If a dish is served pomontier, what does it contain?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a512", "question": "In what country can you find the islands Sylt, Fohr, and Amrum?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ba", "question": "What U.S. state did the Coneheads settle in after crash landing on earth?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd69f486c0f9723ab15cb29", "question": "Who was the first woman to win the Pulitzer Prize?", "answer": "Edith Wharton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42c", "question": "The Himalayas are located on which continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b2bb01dd7bf43be5e7a2", "question": "A group of ferrets is called what?", "answer": "A business", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600243494be4723ccac22194", "question": "Humbert Humbert is the protagonist and narrator of which controversial novel?", "answer": "\"Lolita\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbb", "question": "Whose 1939 nomination for the Nobel Peace Prize was retracted in February of that same year?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a375", "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?", "answer": "Kiev", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b35891a5db0d66a186cb548", "question": "What word is used to identify the residents of Burkina Faso?", "answer": "Burkinabe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe771aceec85e375820b2fc", "question": "What strait separates Australia's mainland from Tasmania?", "answer": "Bass Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358dba5db0d66a186cb563", "question": "If a chemical is \"anhydrous\", what does it not contain?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ccb", "question": "What nursery rhyme character \"kissed the girls and made them cry\"?", "answer": "Georgy Porgy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb23", "question": "What NFL team did the Denver Broncos defeat to win their second Super Bowl?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bec", "question": "What musical featured \"I Could Have Danced All Night\"?", "answer": "My Fair Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358d4b5db0d66a186cb560", "question": "From which South American country do the beers \"Brahma\" and \"Antarctica\" come?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d5", "question": "At the end of \"Planet of the Apes\" what monument protruded from the rocks?", "answer": "Statue of Liberty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5afad88e430e050a5df0d112", "question": "Which brand of soda was the second to be produced by The Coca-Cola Company?", "answer": "Fanta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d116744fea7fe947a22270", "question": "Who played the role of Veronica Quaife in the 1986 film \"The Fly\"?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ca", "question": "Which Shakespeare play tells a love story between a Capulet and a Montague?", "answer": "Romeo and Juliet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0c8b469bb8041d07a052", "question": "What is a light and fluffy pie filling made with stabilized gelatin and beaten egg whites called?", "answer": "Chiffon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e2", "question": "In which Chinese city is the Terracotta Army?", "answer": "Xian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8c32ec223966ae8f8847", "question": "Complete the quote \"I have to remind myself that some birds aren't meant to be\u2026\" from the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "\"Caged\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3400ff048f679a45aaf4", "question": "How do birds help plant new trees and bushes?", "answer": "By eating the fruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df9", "question": "Gene Hackman's \"French Connection\" cop is nicknamed for what cartoon character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74e", "question": "What plant is the most common cause of hay fever?", "answer": "Ragweed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b373541c3f17ccc40c8e2c", "question": "Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\" depicts the courtship of which characters?", "answer": "Petruchio and Katherina", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf64", "question": "George Fox founded which religious group?", "answer": "Quakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8a9f601dd7bf43be5e754", "question": "If there are six apples, and you take away four, how many apples do you have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2c", "question": "What line divided the North and South in the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "The Mason-Dixon line", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf7", "question": "What drink is sometimes called \"La F\u00e9e Verte\"?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af55", "question": "What was the name of the Argentine cruiser sunk after a British attack during the Falklands War in 1982?", "answer": "General Belgrano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bf", "question": "Which French designer was the heir to a fertilizer fortune?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bae", "question": "Which Beethoven symphony became associated with victory in WWII?", "answer": "The Fifth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8be", "question": "What German city is home to a statue called \"The Town Musicians\"?", "answer": "Bremen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68b", "question": "\"Lorgnette\" is the proper term for a pair of glasses with what?", "answer": "A handle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e959fe83fe1f2a824be4", "question": "Who was the first person to be awarded two Nobel prizes?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd87", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kumonga?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d26", "question": "What children's books character lives in the Hundred Acre Woods?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72b", "question": "How do Japanese children refer to Santa Claus?", "answer": "Santa no ojisan or Uncle Santa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2b", "question": "In the Marvel Comics world, who has an assistant named Pepper Potts?", "answer": "Tony Stark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600242c44be4723ccac2218c", "question": "Which James Joyce novel chronicles a day in the life of Leopold Bloom?", "answer": "\"Ulysses\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd6", "question": "In 2001, David McCullough published a biography of which US Founding Father president?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff5151fff04d658268c92e7", "question": "What weapon was developed in 1942 in a secret laboratory at Harvard University?", "answer": "Napalm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fa", "question": "Gregory Peck played Lt. Joe Clemons in what 1950s film?", "answer": "Pork Chop Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8b", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"On the Waterfront\"?", "answer": "Eva Marie Saint", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6d", "question": "What was George Washington's wife's name?", "answer": "Martha", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a068", "question": "What group was Ringo Starr with before the Beatles?", "answer": "Rory Storm and the Hurricanes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cf", "question": "What was Walt Disney's first feature-length animated film?", "answer": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8be1ec223966ae8f8844", "question": "Which television series revolves around a concierge doctor making house calls in the Hamptons?", "answer": "\"Royal Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a03", "question": "Who wrote \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Dan Brown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999e", "question": "How many episodes of \"Petticoat Junction\" were made?", "answer": "222", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a5535d3e1c6f9840ba31a3", "question": "Who won the 1990 Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47b", "question": "When did the Battle of the Plains of Abraham take place?", "answer": "1759", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e19a06d333868d34d728", "question": "How long was Francisco Franco in power in Spain?", "answer": "36 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feccc20ec223966ae8f88a1", "question": "How long did it take to render each frame (1/24th of a second) of the CGI scenes in the movie \"Avatar\"?", "answer": "47 hours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f5", "question": "Which blood type is a universal donor?", "answer": "O negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab2", "question": "Who wrote the Christmas murder-mystery, Star Bright! A Christmas Story?", "answer": "Andrew M. Greeley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65d3e1f3c0ead6880d619", "question": "What Enron CEO took the company to financial disaster?", "answer": "Kenneth Lay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbf", "question": "Stores around the town square of Oxford, Mississippi closed during what author's 1962 funeral?", "answer": "William Faulkner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73f", "question": "What toy company first produced the Spirograph drawing toy back in 1966?", "answer": "Kenner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338941", "question": "What creatures in \"The Lord of the Rings\" are referred to as goblins in the book \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Orcs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8d", "question": "What did Benjamin Franklin do on April 17, 1790?", "answer": "He died", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e91", "question": "What detective novel begins with a dinner hosted by the mysteriously absent \"Mr. U. N. Owen\"?", "answer": "And Then There Were None", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c23", "question": "Who is the author of the Discworld series?", "answer": "Terry Pratchett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1f", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Pool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d80", "question": "What ABC TV star is the great-grandson of a billionaire oilman?", "answer": "Balthazar Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb3355e368446ca7bd6843", "question": "Who is credited with the invention of the Phillips screw design?", "answer": "John P. Thompson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2b", "question": "Who became an animated Disney megastar after replacing Oswald the Lucky Rabbit?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c8", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339392", "question": "Who played the role of Donnie Brasco in the movie of the same name?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f90", "question": "Which character is the narrator of Melville's \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f95aeff55722f97b22684d7", "question": "In the \"Star Wars\" franchise, how many languages is C-3PO fluent in?", "answer": "Over six million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae76", "question": "What Confederate general opened fire on Fort Sumter, beginning the Civil War?", "answer": "General Beauregard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c595", "question": "What part of the body does a Rhinologist specialize in?", "answer": "The nose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d7", "question": "What is the capital of Hawaii?", "answer": "Honolulu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989f", "question": "What movie is set in the year 2154 on the moon of Pandora?", "answer": "Avatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b5", "question": "Which French fashion designer created the conical bra for Madonna's \"Blond Ambition\" tour?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bb", "question": "Who played the role of Lamont Sanford in the TV show \"Sanford and Son\"?", "answer": "Desmond Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c2b24f032c0db195b484", "question": "Which dictator composed six operas?", "answer": "Kim Jong-il was the supreme leader of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008aafcf842fa4c4ba9692", "question": "Who released the 1979 song \"Rock 'n' Roll High School\"?", "answer": "The Ramones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42d", "question": "Which is the largest country in Africa by area?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3b", "question": "On what TV show is Momcorp the world's largest megacorporation?", "answer": "Futurama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cb", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Little Corporal\"?", "answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7a", "question": "What word describes a cut of steak containing both the T-\u00adbone and the tenderloin?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee5", "question": "Who's the palindromic protagonist of Dickens' \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Pip", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339118", "question": "What year saw the release of H. G. Wells' \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "1896", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9047001dd7bf43be5e875", "question": "What can a polyglot do?", "answer": "Know and speak several languages", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b296", "question": "Washington's famous crossing of the Delaware was en route to what Revolutionary War battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a473", "question": "In which ocean are the Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac13", "question": "Which ocean surrounds the Union of the Comoros?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399da", "question": "What 1990 hit song by Jane's Addiction begins with the sound of dogs barking?", "answer": "Been Caught Stealing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e867b24f84e0b9f9ffc3", "question": "Which group released the album \"O.K. Computer\" in 1997?", "answer": "Radiohead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3cff44f0f6af5b066636", "question": "\"Domingo\" is Spanish for what?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a728cf36bcd28c11938328e", "question": "What is Steganography?", "answer": "The practice of concealing a message within another message", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062b3dc9d816e292245c1f", "question": "In which Massachusetts town is \"Little Women\" set?", "answer": "Louisa May Alcott\u2019s semi-autobiographical work takes place in Concord, Massachusetts, where she and her three sisters lived.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a97", "question": "In the novel by Jules Verne, who made it around the world in 80 days?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec0e08d98002fdd633b6", "question": "Which singer wrote the autobiography \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7357feec85e375820b24c", "question": "Who said, \"Personally I\u2019m always ready to learn, although I do not always like being taught.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ac", "question": "The dish \"rosti\" originated from which country?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1f", "question": "In the title of a 1986 song by Lionel Richie, what part of the room was he dancing on?", "answer": "The ceiling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ab8646490a8cc1a6e528c", "question": "What type of bear has a clear eyelid?", "answer": "Polar Bears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53e", "question": "The bone patella is also known as what?", "answer": "The kneecap", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac8", "question": "Tom Petty's video for his song \"Don't Come Around Here No More\" was inspired by what story?", "answer": "Alice in Wonderland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb3", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff14323b0ee8c595b6d39b1", "question": "Which artist painted \"The Gleaners\"?", "answer": "Jean Francois Millet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64c", "question": "A duck-billed platypus is one of the only three mammals in the world that can do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45b", "question": "Where is the Pentagon building physically located?", "answer": "Arlington, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121b4f63c99d48cd169b0d", "question": "\"Astrolatry\" is the worship of what as deities?", "answer": "Celestial bodies -- People who practice astrolatry consider the sun, moon, stars and other celestial bodies as gods.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88b", "question": "What is the point value of the letter Z in a standard Scrabble game?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b11be662d71a53650fce", "question": "What is the name of the giant flame creature the Fellowship faced in the Chamber of Mazarbul?", "answer": "Balrog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d07e91a1c922dd1ac64bd", "question": "Which Science Fiction author wrote \"The Day of the Triffids\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa8", "question": "\"A bushy, bushy blonde hair\u00addo\" is a line from what hit song?", "answer": "Surfin' USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0ca8469bb8041d07a054", "question": "What would you be served in a Japanese restaurant if you ordered \"Takenoko\"?", "answer": "Bamboo shoots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982f", "question": "What war was the setting of the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Korean War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af1", "question": "In which US state was Clark Kent brought up?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88b", "question": "What does the Bark scale measure?", "answer": "Perceived loudness of sounds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6b653fb6c85e9e634ff48", "question": "The fear of men is known as what?", "answer": "Androphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd5", "question": "Run D.M.C. were the first rap band to appear on the cover of what magazine?", "answer": "Rolling Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590683a5ff9c0647b50a80a9", "question": "What is the name of the cable television network VICE Media launched in Canada and the United States in February 2016?", "answer": "Viceland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef631a6ce05a3942286e62", "question": "Who was the first guest on \"Late Night with David Letterman\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a47112f2a7826b9b8730", "question": "A medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels is called a what?", "answer": "Laxative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf29", "question": "What sporting event first took place in 1903?", "answer": "Tour de France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb4", "question": "What is the only first name shared by two members of Monty Python?", "answer": "Terry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596df873f0cc2631d16a3c61", "question": "Florida Georgia Line\u2019s song, \"H.O.L.Y.\", is an acronym for what?", "answer": "High On Lovin\u2019 You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b825", "question": "What Fortune 500 company was name for a Herman Melville character?", "answer": "Starbucks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a580", "question": "How many US states share a land border with Alaska?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b723", "question": "What is Lapland's Korvatunturi Mountain to FInnish children?", "answer": "The location of Santa's workshop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fff6a4edfd43a087add6", "question": "Whose painting \"Irises\" was sold to Alan Bond in 1987?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc08", "question": "What popular figure was born Agnese Gonxhe Bojaxhiu?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d05491a1c922dd1ac64a1", "question": "Which islands were the subject of a war between Argentina and United Kingdom in the 1980s?", "answer": "Falklands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c9f7d0b4e2c7fbd389674c", "question": "Who wrote the essay \"A Nice Cup of Tea\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cd", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Reverend Lovejoy's first name?", "answer": "Timothy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d4172596a59cbdfbd3a1", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba65", "question": "In what year were Sea-\u00adMonkeys first marketed?", "answer": "1957", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c589", "question": "What is an Anhinga?", "answer": "A bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac31", "question": "What was the first railroad to cross the US?", "answer": "The Union Pacific", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a990", "question": "What city named its airport after Galileo Galilei?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af5f", "question": "In addition to his more historic crime, Lee Harvey Oswald was charged with killing what policeman?", "answer": "J. D. Tippit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59524172736d4be723796b62", "question": "Which European countries have an enclave with each other in the region of Baarle-Nassau?", "answer": "Belgium and The Netherlands (Holland)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b9", "question": "What was the first music video that aired on MTV in 1981?", "answer": "Video Killed the Radio Star", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339061", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Samson Agonistes\"?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdb", "question": "Who is Cleveland, Ohio, named after?", "answer": "General Moses Cleveland", "category": "history"}]